<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/matlabicon.gif" type="Source">

    <name>Matlab Snippet</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Executes a snippet with Matlab within Knime.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node executes a snippet/script using an Matlab server. The script for Matlab can be selected from a
                snippet template repository.
                RGG (<a href="http://rgg.r-forge.r-project.org/index.html">R GUI Generator</a>)
                is used to configure the Matlab code using a graphical user interface in a way that the user does not
                need to know scripting in Matlab.
                URL of the template file can be set in Knime->Preferences->Knime->Matlab Scripting
                <br/>
                The input data table is sent to Matlab as a matlab-dataset named "kIn" ("dataset" is part of the
                Statistics Toolbox!). The output data table is sent back to Knime as "mOut".
            </p>
            <p>
                Script Editor:
                <br/>
                Copy, cut or paste and Matlab code to the editor and/or select the columns from your data table. If a
                template is loaded used the GUI to adapt the script to the input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                Templates:
                <br/>
                Select a snippet template from the template repository (double-click or "Use this template") to use that
                script and see the GUI.
                The description explains what a snippet does.
                Then configure the GUI according to your input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                Output Options:
                <br/>
                Specify the output table to avoid that the node shows a warning.
            </p>
            <p>
                IMPORTANT :
                <br/>
                This node is using Matlab as backend, make sure that the Matlab server is running somewhere, and Knime
                is accordingly
                configured (Knime->Preferences->Knime->Matlab Scripting).
                <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/Matlab-server-for-knime">Scripting
                    integration Wiki (Matlab server)
                </a>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Scipt Editor/Unlink from Template">Gives access to the Matlab script after adaptation by the GUI.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Edit Template">Gives access to the RGG script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Refresh">Loads again the template file.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Gallery">Generate a temporary webpage shown in a browser which gives an overview about
            all available templates.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Description,Source">Desciption explains what this snippet does. Source displays the RGG
            script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Use this template">Click to load the GUI (or double-click onto the template)
        </option>
        <option name="Output Options/Add/Remove output columns">Specify the colummn names and types of the output table.
            If this is not done then Knime shows a warning, because the output table is not defined.
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data table returned from the snippet">The data table that the snippet returns
        </outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
