<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icon/pythonicon.gif" type="Source"
	deprecated="true">

	<name>Python Snippet</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Executes a snippet with Python within KNIME.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node executes a snippet/script using Python. The
				script for Python can be selected from a snippet
				template repository. RGG (
				<a href="http://rgg.r-forge.r-project.org/index.html">
					R GUI Generator
				</a>
				) is used to configure the Python code using a graphical
				user interface in a way that the user does not need to
				know scripting in Python. URL of the template file can
				be set in KNIME->Preferences->KNIME->Python Scripting
				<br />
				The input data table from KNIME is converted to a
				dictionary and imported into Python as a variable named
				"kIn". The output data table is sent back to KNIME as
				"pyOut".
			</p>
			<p>
				Script Editor:
				<br />
				Copy, cut or paste and Python code to the editor and/or
				select the columns from your data table. If a template
				is loaded used the GUI to adapt the script to the input
				data.
			</p>
			<p>
				Templates:
				<br />
				Select a snippet template from the template repository
				(double-click or "Use this template") to use that script
				and see the GUI. The description explains what a snippet
				does. Then configure the GUI according to your input
				data.
			</p>
			<p>
				Output Options:
				<br />
				Specify the output table to avoid that the node shows a
				warning.
			</p>
			<p>
				IMPORTANT:
				<br />
				TThis node is using Python as backend, make sure that
				Python is installed locally or that the node can connect
				to the Python server is running somewhere accessible.
				Check the node configurations:
				KNIME->Preferences->KNIME->Python Scripting.
				<br />
				Further documentation can be found on the
				<a
					href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/Python-server-for-knime">
					Scripting integration Wiki (Python server)
				</a>
			</p>
		</intro>

		<option name="Script Editor/Unlink from Template">
			Gives access to the Python script after adaptation by the
			GUI.
		</option>
		<option name="Script Editor/Edit Template">
			Gives access to the RGG script.
		</option>
		<option name="Templates/Refresh">
			Loads again the template file.
		</option>
		<option name="Templates/Gallery">
			Generate a temporary webpage shown in a browser which gives
			an overview about all available templates.
		</option>
		<option name="Templates/Description,Source">
			Description explains what this snippet does. Source displays
			the RGG script.
		</option>
		<option name="Templates/Use this template">
			Click to load the GUI (or double-click onto the template)
		</option>
		<option name="Output Options/Add/Remove output columns">
			Specify the column names and types of the output table. If
			this is not done then KNIME shows a warning, because the
			output table is not defined.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table</inPort>
		<outPort index="0"
			name="Data table returned from the snippet">
			The data table that the snippet returns
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
