<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./pythonicon.gif" type="Sink">

    <name>Open in Python</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Opens Python session with data table from Knime.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node opens a local Python session, converts the data table from Knime into a Python dictionary and
                imports it into the Python session as a variable. If a snippet/script is selected and the GUI
                configured, it is automatically available from the clipboad and can be pasted to Python. This enables
                quick prototyping of a script in Python.
                <br/>
                The input data table is sent to Python and is imported as a variable named "kIn". If the optional input
                ports are used then variables are named "kIn1", "kIn2" and "kIn3".
            </p>
            <p>
                Script Editor:
                <br/>
                Copy, cut or paste and Python code to the editor and/or select the columns from your data table. If a
                template is loaded used the GUI to adapt the script to the input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                Templates:
                <br/>
                Select a snippet template from the template repository (double-click or "Use this template") to use that
                script and see the GUI.
                The description explains what a snippet does.
                Then configure the GUI according to your input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                IMPORTANT :
                <br/>
                This node is using Python as backend, make sure that a Python server is running somewhere, and Knime is
                accordingly
                configured (Knime->Preferences->Knime->Python scripting).
                <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/Python-server-for-knime">Scripting
                    integration Wiki (Python server)
                </a>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Scipt Editor/Unlink from Template">Gives access to the Python script after adaptation by the GUI.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Edit Template">Gives access to the RGG script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Refresh">Loads again the template file.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Gallery">Generate a temporary webpage shown in a browser which gives an overview about
            all available templates.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Description,Source">Desciption explains what this snippet does. Source displays the RGG
            script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Use this template">Click to load the GUI (or double-click onto the template)
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table pushed to Python
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Optional data table 1">First optional data table pushed to Python
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="2" name="Optional data table 2">Second optional data table pushed to Python
        </inPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>