<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../python-logo-generic.png" type="Manipulator">

    <name>Python Snippet 2:2</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Executes Python code.
    </shortDescription>

     <fullDescription>
    
    	<!-- Goes for all Python nodes -->
    	
        <intro>
            <p>
            The node executes Python code. There are two ways to
            configure which code will be executed:

            <ol>
            	<li>Select (Templates Tab; double-click or "Use this template") and configure a Python template from the template repository.</li>
            	<li>Write you own Python code (Script Editor Tab)</li>
            </ol>
            </p>
            <p>The Python installation which is used for execution can be set in the Preferences under <b>KNIME > Community Scripting > Python Scripting</b>. The settings allow to switch between a Python2 and Python3 installation. They further provide to set template resources (URLs or file locations) for either plot and snippet respectively.</p>
            <p>Further, the node can be executed in an <b>'Open External'</b> mode (checkbox at the Script Editor Tab) which then would push the KNIME data to Python for troubleshooting or prototyping (either as a Jupyter notebook or via command line).</p>
            <p>For detailed information check out the <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/Python-Integration"> Wiki Page </a></p>
        </intro>
        
        <!-- Goes for all Python nodes which provide templates -->
        
        <tab name="Templates">
        <option name="Templates/Refresh">Loads again the template file(s).
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Gallery">Generate a temporary webpage shown in a browser which gives an overview about
            all available templates.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Description,Source">Description explains what this snippet does. Source displays the RGG
            script.
        </option><option name="Templates/Use this template">Click to load the GUI (or double-click onto the template)
        </option>
        </tab>

		<!-- Goes for all Python nodes which allows scripting -->
		
		<tab name="Script Editor">
        <option name="Open external">If checked, Python will be opened externally, either as Jupyter notebook or via command line.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Unlink from Template">Gives access to the Python script after adaptation by the GUI.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Edit Template">Gives access to the RGG script to adapt the GUI of a template.
        </option>
        </tab>
        
        
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table (kIn1)">
        	A data table<br/>
        	Provided as pandas data frame named <b>kIn1</b> in Python.
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Data table (kIn2)">
        	A data table<br/>
        	Provided as pandas data frame named <b>kIn2</b> in Python.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data table (pyOut1) returned from Python">
        	he data table that the Python snippet returns.<br/>
        	Expected as pandas data frame named <b>pyOut1</b> in Python
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Data table (pyOut2) returned from Python">
        	he data table that the Python snippet returns.<br/>
        	Expected as pandas data frame named <b>pyOut2</b> in Python
        </outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
