<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./matlabicon.gif" type="Sink">

    <name>Open in Matlab</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Rapid-prototyping in MATLAB for Knime.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <b>This node needs a MATLAB installation on the local machine!</b>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            The node converts the input table into a MATLAB type variable (dataset, map or structure), and makes it
            available
            in MATLAB's workspace as a variable named "kIn". There is also a variable "names", that is a structure
            allowing to associate the actual column names with the variabele names (not needed if the dataset type is
            used).
            <br/>
            If matlab is not running, the node launches an instance of the MATLAB desktop.
            It is recommended to let KNIME start MATLAB the first time. That way the working direcotry of MATLAB will
            be changed to the location where KNIME stores the m-file to load the data in the workspace (manually
            you'll have to change directory into the temp-dir of the JVM that runs KNIME). Also the
            instruction. to re-load the data will be indicated in the Command Window at startup.
            <br/>
            <br/>
            Detailed documentation about the scripting integration:
            <a href="https://wiki.mpi-cbg.de/wiki/sweng/index.php/Knime_Scripting">
                MPI-CBG SWEG Wiki
            </a>
        </intro>

        <option name="Choose the MATLAB type">
            Select the MATLAB type of the variable that will contain the KNIME table
            in the MATLAB workspace
        </option>

        <option name="Run in a new MATLAB instance">
            If checked, each time the node is executed it starts a new matlab
            instance. If unchecked it only starts an MATLAB instance if none is running.
            <br/>
            To re-load the data in matlab type re-execute the m-file in the JVM's temp-dir.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="in1">A table which should be pushed to R.</inPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
