<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="de.mpicbg.tds.knime.scripting.matlab.feature"
      label="KNIME Matlab Scripting extension"
      version="2.0.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="Max Planck Institute of Molecular Cell Biology and Genetics (MPI-CBG)">

   <description url="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki">
      The Matlab Scripting Integration provides a collection of KNIME nodes to develop and integrate matlab scripts
        and templates.
   </description>

   <copyright>
      KNIME Matlab Scripting extension
    Copyright (c) 2014, Max Planck Institute of Molecular Cell Biology and Genetics (MPI-CBG)
	All rights reserved.
   </copyright>

   <license>
      	BSD-License
        -
        TERMS AND CONDITIONS
        -
        Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
        modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
        are met:
        • Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
        notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
        • Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
        notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer
        in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the
        distribution.
        • Neither the name of the MPI-CBG nor the names of its contributors
        may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this
        software without specific prior written permission.
        THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
        &quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT
        NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
        FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT
        SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
        DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
        DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE
        GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS
        INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY,
        WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE
        OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE,
        EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
        -
        END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS
        -

        IMPORTANT NOTICE:
        It is the obligation of every user to abide terms and conditions
        of The MathWorks, Inc. Software License Agreement.
        In particular Article 8 “Web Applications”: it is permissible
        for an Application created by a Licensee of the
        NETWORK CONCURRENT USER ACTIVATION type to use MATLAB as a remote
        engine with static scripts.
   </license>

   <plugin
         id="de.mpicbg.knime.scripting.matlab"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>
         
	<plugin
         id="de.mpicbg.knime.scripting.matlab.srv"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"/>

</feature>
