<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./ricon.png" type="Manipulator">

    <name>R Snippet</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Executes an R script within KNIME.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node executes a snippet/script using an R server (Rserve). The script for R can be selected from a
                snippet template repository.
                RGG (<a href="http://rgg.r-forge.r-project.org/index.html">R GUI Generator</a>)
                is used to configure the R code using a graphical user interface in a way that the user does not need to
                know scripting in R.
                URL of the template file can be set in KNIME->Preferences->KNIME->R-Scripting
                <br/>
                The input data table is sent to R as a data frame named 'kIn'. The output data table is pulled from R. 
                It has to be an R data frame named 'rOut'.
            </p>
            <p>
                Script Editor:
                <br/>
                Copy, cut or paste and R code to the editor and/or select the columns from your data table. If a
                template is loaded used the GUI to adapt the script to the input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                Templates:
                <br/>
                Select a snippet template from the template repository (double-click or "Use this template") to use that
                script and see the GUI.
                The description explains what a snippet does.
                Then configure the GUI according to your input data.
            </p>
            <p>
                IMPORTANT :
                <br/>
                This node is using R as back end, make sure that Rserve is running somewhere, and KNIME is accordingly
                configured (KNIME->Preferences->KNIME->R-Scripting).
                <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/R-server-for-knime">Scripting integration
                    Wiki (R server)
                </a>
            </p>
        </intro>

		<option name="Open external">If checked, R will be opened externally, the KNIME input will be loaded as data frame 
		and the script will be available at the clipboard.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Unlink from Template">Gives access to the R script after adaptation by the GUI.
        </option>
        <option name="Scipt Editor/Edit Template">Gives access to the RGG script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Refresh">Loads again the template file.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Gallery">Generate a temporary webpage shown in a browser which gives an overview about
            all available templates.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Description,Source">Description explains what this snippet does. Source displays the RGG
            script.
        </option>
        <option name="Templates/Use this template">Click to load the GUI (or double-click onto the template)
        </option>
        
        <option name="Chunk size to push incoming data">
        Number of columns to push as one data chunk to R. The default (-1) leads to data transfer without splitting the data in chunks.
        </option>
        <option name="Chunk size to pull result data">
        	Number of rows to push as one data chunk to R. The default (-1) leads to data transfer without splitting the data in chunks.
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Data table returned from the snippet">The data table that the snippet returns
        </outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
