<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/matlabicon.gif" type="Sink">
    <name>Open in Matlab</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Opens Matlab session with data table from Knime.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node opens a local Matlab session and pushes the data table from Knime into Matlab. If a
                snippet/script is selected and the GUI configured, it is automatically available from the clipboad and
                can be pasted into Matlab. This enables quick prototyping of a script in Matlab.
                <br/>
                The input data table is converted into a Matlab type variable (dataset, map or structure), and made
                available
                in the Matlab workspace as a variable named "kIn". There is also a variable "names", that is a structure
                allowing to associate the actual column names with the variabele names (not needed if the dataset type
                is
                used). If the optional input ports are used then data frames are named "kIn1", "kIn2" and "kIn3".
                <br/>
                <b>This node needs a Matlab installation on the local machine!</b>
                <br/>
                If Matlab is not running, the node launches an instance of the Matlab desktop.
                It is recommended to let KNIME start Matlab the first time. That way the working direcotry of Matlab
                will
                be changed to the location where KNIME stores the m-file to load the data in the workspace (manually
                you'll have to change directory into the temp-dir of the JVM that runs KNIME). Also the
                instructions to re-load the data will be indicated in the Command Window at startup.
            </p>
            <p>
                IMPORTANT :
                <br/>
                This node is using Matlab as backend, make sure that a Matlab server is running somewhere, and Knime is
                accordingly
                configured (Knime->Preferences->Knime->Matlab Scripting).
                <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/Matlab-server-for-knime">Scripting
                    integration Wiki (Matlab server)
                </a>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <option name="Choose the Matlab type">
            Select the Matlab type of the variable that will contain the KNIME table in the Matlab workspace
        </option>
        <option name="Run in a new Matlab instance">
            If checked, each time the node is executed a new Matlab instance will be started. If unchecked a Matlab
            instance will be started if none is running.
            <br/>
            To re-load the data in Matlab type re-execute the m-file in the JVM's temp-dir.
        </option>

    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table pushed to Matlab
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Optional data table 1">First optional data table pushed to Matlab
        </inPort>
        <inPort index="2" name="Optional data table 2">Second optional data table pushed to Matlab
        </inPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>