<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../icons/matlabicon.gif" type="Sink">
    <name>Open in Matlab</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Opens Matlab session with data table from KNIME.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node opens a local Matlab session and pushes the data table from Knime into Matlab for rapid prototyping.
                Starting from the Matlab variable containing the KNIME data, a script can be developed and tested, 
                before putting it into a Matlab snippet node.
            </p>
            <p>
                The input data table is converted into a Matlab type variable (dataset, table, container.Map or structure), and made
                available in the Matlab workspace as a variable named <i>kIn</i>. There is also a variable <i>columnMapping</i>, 
                that is a structure allowing to associate the KNIME column names with the Matlab variable names 
                (not needed if the dataset or table type is used).<br/>
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>This node needs a Matlab installation on the local machine!</b><br/>
                If Matlab is not running, the node launches an instance of the Matlab desktop.
                It is recommended to let KNIME launch Matlab. The node can detect open Matlab instances, 
                but this is not foolproof. The working directory of Matlab will be changed to the location 
                where KNIME stores the m-file to load the data in the workspace (manually
                you'll have to change directory into the temp-dir of the JVM that runs KNIME).
            </p>
            <p>
                <b>Conventions:</b>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        Snippet/Plot input variable name: <i>kIn</i>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Snippet output variable name: <i>mOut</i>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Plot output: the node will create one figure. The snippet will create a graph on that figure.
                        Finally an image will be saved of this figure and pushed back to KNIME. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Supported Matlab types: <i>dataset</i>, <i>table</i>, <i>struct</i> or <i>container.Map</i>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        While the script input type is defined by the preferences,
                        the output type will be inferred from the output variable
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Templates repositories are controlled via the preferences
                        (Menu > KNIME > Preferences > KNIME > Matlab Scripting).
                    </li>
                </ul>
             </p>    
             <p>
             	<b>Further reading:</b>
             	<ul>
             		<li>
             		   Further documentation can be found on the 
					   <a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki">wiki</a><br/>
				   </li>
				   <li>
                		To understand how to use flow variables in the script, please consult 
                		<a href="https://github.com/knime-mpicbg/knime-scripting/wiki/RGG-XML#Flow_variables">RGG XML</a>
            		</li>
        		</ul>
            </p>
        </intro>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data table">A data table pushed to Matlab</inPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>